[dramatic music]
[sighs]
We do this too,
you know.
- What's that?
- Silence as a weapon.
Make people uneasy.
Make 'em talk.
I get paid whether
you talk or not, Teresa.
CBI's been paying you
for five weeks now, doctor.
This was supposed to be routine.
Routine, like, you have to see
me after a shooting? Sure.
Not routine like
I have to sign off on you.
I didn't even pull the trigger
on Tanner. Jane did.
You signed off on him
after one session.
He has good mental health.
Now I wanna see
your license to practice.
- Ha ha.
- Ah, "ha ha."
I've got six open cases.
I'm testifying in two more. I--
It's not as if you have
anything to talk about.
Mom dead when you were 12.
Three younger brothers.
Abusive, alcoholic dad,
now dead also.
It doesn't say abusive.
[dramatic music]
But he was, yes?
This coffee tastes
like crap, seriously.
- Are we done?
- No.
Let's talk about
what you wanna talk about.
- 'What do you do for fun?'
- Fun?
That thing
when you're not working..
I, uh, what does
this have to do--
[cell phone ringing]
Lisbon.
'Yeah, I'll be right there.'
Duty calls. I get it.
Dr. Carmen?
Why won't you sign off on me?
Because there's something
you wanna tell me first.
I'll see you next week.
[music continues]
How did we catch this one?
Switchboard got
an anonymous call
saying there's a dead body.
It's two blocks from us.
Here we are.
- There's just one problem.
- No body?
No body.
Oh, not the dumpsters.
Please, not the dumpsters.
Look around for the body.
See what you see.
Shrink day, huh?
- No.
- Yes. Yes.
You have the line between
your eyebrows. He annoys you.
And besides, you smell
a little of his cigar smoke.
I'm annoyed because
I forgot my cell phone.
Oh, right.
- Cho, anything?
- 'Nothin'.'
[instrumental music]
Did you know that if
you weighed every living thing
on planet Earth, a quarter of
that biomass would be just ants?
- That's a lot of ants.
- It is.
Cho, anything?
No sign of a body.
Alright,
then look in the dumpsters.
Let's get out of here.
- I did it last time.
- Oh, man, I just got this suit.
[Cho]
'Alright, rock, paper, scissors,
on three, ready?'
- One, two, three.
- Yes!
It's been dry this fall, huh?
No rain.
- Like tinder.
- Mmm.
That's why those ants
are looking for moisture
wherever they can find it.
Then why aren't all the ants
in the wet, stinky dumpsters?
Exactly, because they've found
somewhere else
'where there's a little
more m--'
Oh! Rigsby?
'Little help here.'
Oh, please.
[door creaks]
[dramatic music]
[Rigsby]
'Looks like three to the chest,
point-blank.'
Perfect triangle formation.
[Cho]
'No brass,
looks like the shooter took'
'the shell casings
with him. Pro job.'
[Rigsby]
'I can't find any ID.'
'Call forensics.
Run him for prints.'
Who is he?
Name's William McTeer
from San Francisco.
Serial child rapist.
Served six years at Pelican Bay.
And you know this how?
I'm the one
who sent him there.
Ah!
We're near Marie's Donuts.
Anyone wanna go
for a bear claw after?
[dramatic music]
Can't say I'm hungry.
[theme music]
[instrumental music]
Jane, we have a case.
You think I've time for games?
Life is a game. You have
plenty of time for that. Shh!
Shh! I'm gonna read
your thoughts.
I want you to take
a deep breath in..
[inhales deeply]
...and out.
Will you concentrate?
Name as many 20th century
presidents as you can...now.
Uh, Coolidge, Wilson,
Roosevelt, um..
...Eisenhower, Truman,
Kennedy, Nixon, L.B.J.
Good.
Take another breath in.
[inhales deeply]
And out.
[exhaling]
Concentrate on which mug
it is under.
I am listening
to your thoughts.
Don't shout.
I can hear you.
Open your eyes.
[instrumental music]
Well, you did have
a 25 percent shot.
We could do it...all day,
and I would get it every time.
Give me that.
How do you do it?
You told me, Lisbon.
Our minds are in sync.
In fact, right now, right now,
I'm feeling something.
I'm getting it right here.
It's a, it's a nickname.
Saint...Teresa.
How come you never told me
how you know Agent Bosco?
Look, another one. Lisbon was
like a rock star for a while.
What's with her hair?
- What's wrong with my hair?
- 'Nothin'.'
The McTeer case made your career
and you never said a word.
You're like a superhero
with a secret identity.
Uh, you wanna know the deal?
Fine...McTeer hit
the bay area for 18 months.
He attacked seven girls between
the ages of six and nine.
I was the SFPD inspector
who caught it.
I inspected, took McTeer down.
Now, what do you got?
BFS found the shooter's gun
a block away in a trash bin.
They're running it
for prints now.
"Inspector Lisbon's actions
were lauded as heroic
"by city officials
and her SFPD colleagues.
Said her supervisor,
Lieutenant Samuel Bosco.."
"Inspector Lisbon
did an exemplary job
tracking down
and arresting this animal."
Well, that's pretty good.
You should get an act together.
- 'Can you do Barbra Streisand?'
- Don't tempt me.
So I heard about McTeer.
Weird, huh? I mean, here we are
again, after how many years?
Too many.
Have you spoken to Dreyer?
'He'd be my favorite.'
Dreyer Whelan,
father of the last victim
Katie, seven years old, promised
to kill McTeer on release.
I called him. He's on his way
down from Moran.
You're all over it.
Let me know
if you need any help..
...for old times' sake.
For old times' sake.
Here's McTeer's address.
Parole officer says
he's got a live-in girlfriend.
- Go and talk to her.
- He has a girlfriend?
- I think I'll go with her.
- Good idea.
Rigsby, check up
on McTeer's old friends
from the pedophile world
especially those who might
have moved from
San Francisco to Sacramento.
Sure, boss.
Cho and I have a trial meeting
with the deputy AG.
Not if I throw myself
into oncoming traffic first.
[instrumental music]
Miss Derask,
what was your relationship
with William McTeer?
- He was my fiance.
- Fiance.
You have a problem with that?
Oh, she just can't see how
a woman could fall in love
with a convicted pedophile,
not, uh..
'...the best husband material.'
Bill was a good man,
a good provider.
And he treated me like a queen.
Those charges in San Francisco
were totally bogus anyway.
That bitch cop
had it in for him.
A vendetta
is what Bill called it.
You gotta learn how
to clean that trap, Tanya.
That's where the clog..
[sighs]
- Hey.
It's the police, about Bill.
My brother came over
to fix the sink for me.
- David.
- Patrick.
- Hey.
- That's Grace.
David, do you know
William McTeer?
I met him a couple of times.
He treated Tanya good,
so, you know..
Anyway, I just gotta reattach it
and you're all set, T.
Nice meeting you guys.
[Jane]
'You, too.'
Do you know anyone who
would wanna harm William?
Well, i-it's probably
nothin' but..
...he had a fight
with his boss last week.
Came home all moody.
Said the guy was out to get him.
- Who's his boss?
- Some pipsqueak. I don't know.
Uh, XXXYZ Incorporated is
the name of the place, I think.
It's, uh, over on Winley,
near the highway.
[door opens]
- Hey, mommy.
- Hey, Emily, baby.
'How was school?'
[Emily]
'I can multiply my sixes.'
- Wanna hear?
- Wow.
Maybe a little later, okay?
Bill wasn't who you think.
Hey, Emily.
I'm Patrick.
- How are you?
- Good.
- Good day, huh?
- Mm-hmm.
Six times tables, huh?
Wow.
Why don't you go
into the kitchen
and help your Uncle David?
It's okay, sweetie.
See ya.
[Emily]
'Hi, David.'
I don't think
McTeer touched Emily.
See? I told you.
Because he was still
grooming her.
You don't know what
you're talking about.
You met Bill at a shopping mall,
didn't you?
Near the video arcade
or-or the movie theatre.
Emily was with you.
He worked there back then.
Yeah. Real gentleman,
not like your other guys.
He-he never pressured you
to have sex.
It wasn't love at first sight,
but he was just so good
'with Emily.
He listened to her.'
Nobody listened to you
like that, growing up.
Bill wanted to be a father.
My girl doesn't deserve
a father?
Lately, he'd been asking
if he could take Emily away
on an overnight trip,
maybe camping.
A little father-daughter
bonding.
'He'd been pressuring you
to say yes, just a little..'
But just enough
to start to nag you.
A tiny,
little scratching nag..
'...that maybe what you felt
deep down was right.'
William McTeer..
'...was too good to be true.'
[dramatic music]
[sighs]
You deserve a good man, Tanya.
If you can't believe that
for yourself
then just pretend,
for Emily's sake.
We done here? Good,
cause I gotta eat. I'm starving.
Yeah.
Alright.
[door opens]
You each are the state's
key witnesses
in a few cases this month.
Agent Lisbon,
you've got Howard and Ang.
Agent Cho, you've got Ringman,
Daily and Freed.
Freed. Freed bit me.
And be sure to mention
that on the stand.
'Teresa, you remember Howard?'
'He and his syndicate
stole $100 million'
from the online accounts
of thousands of people.
And then he stashed the money
and killed his partner?
I remember him.
The guy's creepy.
Guy's going to prison.
Thanks to Agent Lisbon
and her cool, calm expertise.
That's me, cool and calm.
So glad this isn't a Jane case.
You havegotto tell him,
Teresa, that he cannot
threaten people with bombs
to get a confession.
'No rubber masks,
no monster suits--'
Hey, we have a problem.
BFS got a print off the gun
that killed McTeer.
- And that's a problem?
- Yeah.
Boss, the print is yours.
[dramatic music]
[Minelli]
'Your fingerprint
is on the magazine'
of the murder weapon.
Tell me why I shouldn't
be throwing up
in the bathroom right now.
It's a lab error.
It must be.
They're overworked
and underfunded.
This happened last year
with the LAPD.
Just have them retest it.
Come on!
You don't think I did this.
What I think is, I'm up to my
asterisk in political quicksand.
You and your team are off
the McTeer case, obviously.
I understand.
Are we throwing it to the FBI?
[scoffs]
No.
Hey, Lisbon.
- How about this, huh?
- Bosco.
He knows as much about
the McTeer case as you do.
It makes sense.
And, yes,
I had to pull some strings.
Thank you, I guess.
No, no, don't,
don't misunderstand me.
If you're guilty,
I want you nailed.
I just don't want the feebs
strolling around my offices
asking impertinent questions.
Okay.
So you understand,
I have to ask you
some questions now?
'Nothing personal.'
Absolutely. Shoot.
Hey, everybody.
Uh, well, I bet you wish
you wore some gloves, huh?
- So you have some input here?
- No. Just nosy.
It's okay. He can stay
if he wants to.
I'll stay.
Where were you, Tuesday night?
I was at home, watching
television. Nobody saw me.
- What did you watch?
- Some reality show.
Which?
Cooking show, with the man.
- Oh, yeah. That one.
- 'The angry man. Yeah.'
Oh, I know the one.
That's good.
Cooking show. Tuesday nights.
- 'Yeah.'
- Angry man.
So I can, uh, set up a time
for you to take a polygraph.
[dramatic music]
No.
I didn't kill McTeer.
Nobody said you did yet.
Yet?
Good luck with the case.
[music continues]
Having lunch?
A discussion,
about Lisbon's situation.
Okay, Cho, you say
work the McTeer case hard
screw Bosco and Minelli,
you disagree
and you're not so sure.
I'm just saying, maybe
we should let Bosco do his job.
Stay out of his way.
He's a good cop.
Is anybody gonna go as hard
after this case as us?
I don't think so.
Well, you're assuming
Lisbon didn't kill him.
What if she did kill him?
What would you do?
What would youdo?
Me? I'd walk away.
But I ain't the law.
Yes, we walk away.
- Yeah.
- 'I disagree.'
McTeer went after
little children.
Hey, maybe he deserved to die.
If Lisbon has the guts
to kill him
she has the guts
to serve her time for it.
I'm gonna talk
to McTeer's boss.
- I'll come with you.
- Okay, okay.
Look, Lisbon didn't do it
anyhow.
I mean, right?
She's not capable of that.
I'm not so sure.
[dramatic music]
What's up that we couldn't
talk inside? I'm busy.
Thought you might wanna be
outside so you could
express your anger
without constraint.
Why?
I know you lied about the alibi.
I didn't lie.
I don't know what
you did on Tuesday night
but you weren't watching TV.
I didn't lie.
He made risotto.
Now this is insulting. You're
gonna continue lying to me?
[dramatic music]
I can't remember.
I can't remember what I did
on Tuesday night. It's weird.
Thank you. And it's okay.
The memory's there.
We can get it back. If
I put you in a light trance--
Like that's gonna happen.
Stop trying to hypnotize me.
What if something
traumatic happened
and you're blocking it out?
I didn't kill McTeer.
Well, let me hypnotize you
so we can be sure.
- No.
- Why not?
'Cause I don't want you
inside my head.
So it turns out you're not
quite done with the McTeer case.
- Funny.
- It's not my choice.
- He'll only talk to you.
- 'Who?'
- Agent Lisbon.
- Hello, Dreyer.
[Bosco]
'Thanks for coming in
and helping us out, Mr. Whelan.'
So, you guys are still
working together?
Still a team?
We're both handling
this interview
at your request, Dreyer.
We just have a couple
questions for you.
Just one, in fact.
Did you kill William McTeer?
I didn't.
Glad to hear it.
How's Katie doing?
She's well.
Doing well.
Healing better than I am
according to our therapist.
Where were you, Tuesday night?
At home, alone.
Katie spent the night
at a friend's.
And what time--
- You let him hurt her.
- Excuse me?
I recently read
the incident files.
[Bosco]
'The internal SFPD files?'
How did you get hold of those?
You could have taken McTeer
down the Friday before.
A whole week earlier.
That was not the case.
I didn't have it.
I didn't have any--
And in the meantime,
he attacked Katie.
And you could have saved her.
If I'd arrested him
on a hunch
he would have been acquitted.
He would have walked.
But Katie wouldn't
have been raped.
And thatis your fault.
[dramatic music]
[Bosco]
'Mr. Whelan.'
What?
You swore you'd spend
your entire fortune
in the service of killing
William McTeer.
- Why didn't you?
- I couldn't.
What if I'd been caught?
I couldn't leave Katie alone.
My take? Maybe you just
didn't have the guts.
Go to hell, both of you.
[Bosco]
'Don't worry about it.
He's angry.'
Anger turns you.
Yes, it does.
I wanna take the polygraph.
[dramatic music]
[indistinct]
[keys clacking]
How long did McTeer
work for you?
Uh, couple of months.
His record
didn't bother you?
Nah, freaks work harder,
you know?
They're grateful for the gig,
Not McTeer, though.
Is that why you two
got in a fight?
Me and him?
No, we didn't get in a fight.
He got in a fight with
his jackal buddy, Dog.
They got in a fight right here
in the middle of the place.
Busted it all up.
So I fired his twisted ass.
I mean, that's management 101,
you know, no fist fights.
So I booted him.
He come back at you about that?
No, he knows better than that.
He knows I'm connected.
Connected, really? To whom?
Oh! People?
So what was it about?
McTeer's fight with Dog?
[sighs]
I don't know.
Could have been about
a million things, you know?
Dog was a utility idiot.
'He's dumb
in ten different ways.'
- Dog have a real name?
- 'Everybody does.'
I don't know what his was.
Oh, those are on special.
Buy one, get one free.
No, thanks.
[female #1]
'People vs. Milton R. Howard.'
'Case number 97T03254,
come on down.'
Agent Lisbon,
we have to talk.
How about you give me
a confession, Howard?
Agent, I-I didn't do
these things they said I did.
Okay? Y-you have to hear
my side of it.
I'll see you inside.
Agent Lisbon.
Virgil, talk to her after.
We're up.
Agent Lisbon will not
be joining you.
Is my team okay?
Is somebody hurt?
No. You failed the poly,
Agent Lisbon.
"Significant indications
of deception," they say.
You're relieved of duty, agent.
Report to admin for processing.
- Boss.
- Don't.
[dramatic music]
Signature on the bottom.
Gun and badge in the tray.
[gun clicks]
[music continues]
Here's your receipt.
Have a nice day.
[Dr. Carmen]
'Teresa Lisbon in my office,
talking.'
You must be desperate.
I failed the polygraph.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Well, reading polys
is more art than a science.
Ask to retake it.
I can teach you how to relax.
[dramatic music]
My father used to have blackouts
when he drank.
One time, he beat my brother
half to death
and he didn't remember a thing.
The whole way to the hospital,
he couldn't believe
it was him who did it.
'Are you drinking?'
Is that why you are talking
of blackouts?
What I need to know is,
is-is it possible
that I killed McTeer
and blotted it out?
You can't remember
the night of the murder?
Well, don't panic.
There could be lots of reasons.
'Stress or--'
Cops can become killers,
doctor.
- It can happen.
- It's ridiculous.
You didn't even know
McTeer was in Sacramento.
His parole officer
called me last month.
Courtesy heads-up.
Well..
Can memory loss be a result
of trauma? Sure.
Your mind shields you
from the awful thing you did
or even what someone else did.
Child molesters
don't get better.
The killer saved a child's life,
whoever it is.
How do I unblock my memory?
Maybe it will come back
on its own. Give it time.
I don't have time.
You-you're useless.
- You and all your talking.
- I'm sorry.
Until you remember,
I don't know how to help you.
[dramatic music]
Jane.
Mmm.
Oh, hey, Lisbon.
I imagine you want me
to hypnotize you now.
- Yeah.
- 'Mm-hmm.'
Nothing in McTeer's parole files
about any Dog.
No known associates, either.
Black widow...dead one.
[Bosco]
'What the hell do you think
you're doing?'
Killing a spider.
What are youdoing?
You're interfering with my case.
You're talking to witnesses.
You're wrong.
- You gonna lie to me now?
- What's the problem?
Drop the McTeer case,
or you'll be on guard duty
at the state capital,
saluting tourists.
Is that right?
Yes, it is.
- Nice comeback.
- 'You told him.'
He knows the score.
May I?
Thanks. My guy at Pelican Bay
came through.
Uh, McTeer had a cellmate
for two years..
'...nicknamed Dog.'
[Van Pelt]
'Hey, we know this guy.'
That's the brother
of McTeer's girlfriend.
David Charles.
[dramatic music]
[door opens]
It's kind of a mess.
Not at all.
It's nice.
I like those pictures.
Those are mostly
from the last tenants.
Uh, where-where
are we gonna do this?
Ah, interesting.
Let's just do it. Let-let's go.
- No.
- No?
No, I'm not gonna
hypnotize you, Lisbon.
- You're, you're too stressed.
- Are you kidding me?
No, it's okay, shh!
It's okay, alright?
I'd have to make all
the stress leave your body.
Maybe have you count down
from 100, 99, 98.
We'd go round and round.
94, 93..
Listen to me, Lisbon.
All the stress
would have to melt away.
You'd have to feel calm
and relaxed and very safe.
It's just about impossible.
I'm not hypnotizing you, Lisbon.
It's not gonna happen,
so you can just relax.
You are not falling into
a deep, relaxing trance state.
[instrumental music]
Sleep.
Okay. Good.
Alright.
'So you're going down
the steps.'
'Relaxing with each step.'
And now you reach the bottom.
The very last step.
The ultimate place of calm.
How are you feeling?
Good.
You're gonna remain
in this relaxed trance state
'while we think
about Tuesday night.'
But first..
...sometimes you dance to that
Spice Girls CD, don't you?
Yeah.
I thought so.
Now, Tuesday.
You can watch the whole day
like it's a movie.
Every detail is in focus.
You can zoom
into any moment you want.
You can fast-forward, rewind.
Youare in total control, okay?
Okay.
Good.
What do you see?
I'm finishing up the Form 41s
on the Milbank case.
I feel..
...hungry,
'cause I skipped lunch.
The new guy
in the mailroom is hot.
- Is he?
- Yeah.
Let's fast-forward a little.
Later in the day..
...you're about to leave CBI.
Van Pelt's working late.
She's a hard worker.
She might do well if she manages
not to sleep with Rigsby.
Where do you go now?
I..
Home?
Do you?
Where-where-where
do you go, Lisbon?
I'm in my car.
It's low on gas.
[breathing heavily]
It's okay.
You're in a trance state.
Everything is okay.
- I can't--
- What do you see?
Where do you go?
I...I don't..
It's blank.
- I just see a blank screen.
- It's alright.
It's alright.
[breathing heavily]
I don't..
I don't know where I went.
I-I-I can't remember.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
I can't remember.
That's a little weird.
[sighs]
I thought you were the best.
'I want my money back.'
Hmm. Yeah.
Why can't I remember?
It's interesting, isn't it?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's interesting.
Hmm.
Well, you know,
th-thanks for trying.
You probably have, uh,
somewhere you need to go, right?
Well, I'm not gonna
give up that easily.
[dramatic music]
I can count on you not to tell
anybody about this, right?
On the team?
Oh, Lisbon.
- Hey.
- Jane.
I just need you to leave, okay?
- Alright.
- Could you please go?
It's-it's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be fine, alright?
I promise.
- Okay?
- Mm-hmm.
Tanya? I got your text.
It said 911.
What's going on?
[grunts]
Oh! hey, help, police!
Relax, buddy.
Yeah, we're clear. You good?
[Cho]
'Yeah.'
You fought with McTeer
in the parking lot.
He beat the snot out of you.
That must have been
pretty humiliating.
So you lured him into the alley
and you killed him.
No, I didn't kill him.
I didn't!
You didkill him, David.
You killed him.
But it's our friend
on the hook for it.
Look, Dog, jail is gonna
be so much better
than what you get
if you keep lying to us.
Look, your friend, the cop..
She's the one who paid me
to bring McTeer to the alley.
Look, I had no idea she was
gonna shoot him, I swear to you.
I never would have taken
the money if I knew it.
Agent Lisbon,
she's the one who paid you?
Yeah, I mean,
it had to be her, didn't it?
I heard you guys already
arrested her for it.
But you're guessing, right?
You never actually saw her.
Well, I didn't see anybody.
It was all text.
The deal was I got Bill drunk.
We went out in the alley to go
take a pee, and then I split.
I heard those shots. I just
started running like hell, man.
'And the next day,
there's ten grand'
in my checking account.
Ten grand?
- 'Ten grand, Sam.'
- I heard.
Ten grand just to lure
the vic in, not even kill him.
This is somebody
with resources, connections.
[Cho]
Someone who's not Lisbon.
Seriously, where's she gonna
get ten grand from?
No offense, boss.
I will have Van Pelt
track the text.
Cho and I will talk
to the guy's bank.
Lisbon, get this
through your head.
You're relieved of duty.
You're not even supposed
to be in the building
and you two clowns
are wayout of hand.
Let me deal with this.
Come here.
Lisbon, look at me. Look at me.
I'll handle it.
Will you please trust me?
I'm sorry.
You don't understand.
Later, you will.
What are-are-are you
medicated or something?
Okay, I'm alright.
I'm fine.
What the hell is everybody
looking at? I'm fine!
Just stay the hell away from me.
I'm done with this crap.
I am done.
Get out of my way.
I'm sick of everybody.
[dramatic music]
What was that, Lisbon?
[Rigsby]
'She's freaking out.'
Oh, come on.
It's just Lisbon.
- She's a little stressed.
- What is going on?
Sorry.
- Why is this happening to me?
- It's alright.
- Let's-let's go home.
- I'll take her.
No. Leave me alone.
[music on earphones]
[dramatic music]
The ten grand paid
to David Charles
came from an account owned by
a shell company in the Caymans.
Well, that's good.
The day after it paid David
the account paid out a million
dollars to someone else.
I bet that's for the shooter.
Can we trace the payment?
Uh, I'm trying, but--
You'll find it dead-ends
in a blind account
that was closed yesterday.
Okay. We are working
the case. We just want to--
Forget about it. How's Lisbon?
She's fine.
Well, what did she say,
exactly?
Well, I didn't actually
talkto her.
She-she wouldn't let me in.
'You're worried about her.'
You think she might do
something stupid?
Suicide? No.
If she did,
she wouldn't blame the bureau.
That's not my concern at all.
I should've taken her
off-duty weapon.
Oh, I'm sure she'll be alright.
[knock on door]
Minelli asked me to drop by.
Well, ordered me
to drop by, actually.
- Can we talk?
- Minelli?
He's worried about you.
We all are.
'Cause I had a meltdown?
Got perp-walked out of the CBI?
'Or because I killed a guy?'
[dramatic music]
Wh...youkilled McTeer?
How the hell would I know?
Maybe?
Uh, Teresa, you-you wanna
put away your Glock there?
Very good eye, doctor.
The Glock, 9 millimeter.
The safety's in the trigger.
How stupid is that?
I mean, it's kind of like
not having a safety at all.
How about you give it to me?
Don't look at me like that.
This is your fault.
Well, Teresa..
You unlocked too many things
in my head
and now I can't remember.
My head is messed up,
and it's your fault.
Teresa..
...put it down.
'You need to be calm..'
...and put down the gun.
Calm?
You were right, doctor.
There was something
I wanted to tell you.
I act calm on the outside,
but on the inside
I'm so angry, sometimes
I think I'm gonna explode.
All the misery and the pain
that I see every day
makes me wanna scream,
but I lock it down.
I lock it down because
I have to be calm and rational
because that's my job,
but I wanna pull this trigger.
I wanna kill.
You're angry. I hear that.
[dramatic music]
I think I did it.
I think I killed McTeer.
Shh, Teresa.
'If you did it..'
'...that's okay.'
He was a bad man.
No reason for you
to hurt anyone else..
...or yourself.
- I still can't remember.
- You can and you will.
And when you do, Teresa, when
you push through to the truth
all this weight and worry
will come off your shoulders.
Okay.
'I want you..'
...to visualize
that scene for me.
Relive that moment.
You went into the alley..
...after this terrible man.
Can you see him?
No.
Well, yes. Yeah, m-maybe.
Yes. You see him.
You see the dumpsters
and the trash
and the crumbly, old brick,
and you see McTeer.
You see him there,
this-this monster
who destroyed so many lives.
It's too much.
'See it, Teresa.'
[gunshots]
Live it..
...the reek, the garbage.
The filthy alley walls.
The faded cross there.
God might have mercy
on William McTeer
but you sure as hell wouldn't.
He deserved to die.
'But you're still
a good person, Teresa.'
'You can get through this.'
The cross?
Uh, what?
The cross, Roy.
'How did you know
about the cross?'
It was inside the door.
Only the killer saw it.
Well, Teresa, you told me
about the crime scene.
No, I didn't.
[gunshots]
[Jane]
'Oh, beautifully done.'
'Lovely work, Lisbon.'
What are you..
Of course, the cross.
You couldn't resist
the imagery, could you, doc?
- Lapsed Catholic, perhaps?
- What's going on?
Surrender, Dorothy.
We got you. Brilliant, though.
Made Lisbon come back
week after week
so you get her fingerprints
off your coffee mug
and dose her up
with, uh, Lorazepam?
Double dose for Tuesday
to cause the memory loss.
Memory loss you knew
Lisbon would conceal
which made her fail
the polygraph.
Quite the, uh, student
of human nature, huh, doctor?
Well done, really.
Your breakdown in CBI,
that was fake?
[Jane]
'And how good was that, huh?
What about that?'
After that, all I had
to do was get Minelli
to get you to come
around here.
I've been waiting for you
all night.
There was one little thing.
I'm-I'm just,
just one little thing.
The Lorazepam? Maybe
that went a little too far.
When-when Lisbon couldn't
remember the night of the murder
even under hypnosis,
I knew she'd been drugged.
The rest of it? Spot on.
Very, very impressive.
- Thanks.
- Not at all.
[instrumental music]
[grunts]
You're under arrest. You have
the right to remain silent.
Anything you say or do
can and will be used
against you in court.
'You have the right
to an attorney.'
So this guy who gave you
the million bucks.
You ever met him
face-to-face?
You want him?
I want a deal, a good one.
What I got, it's worth it.
Two to five, minimum security.
Oh, there won't be a deal.
We know who he is.
Just curious if youknew.
[instrumental music]
[Van Pelt]
'It took us a while
but we traced the shell company'
'back to you, Howard.'
You paid Dr. Carmen
and David Charles
to frame Lisbon
for McTeer's murder.
These cash transactions
prove it.
Discrediting a cop is so much
smarter than killing her.
'We'd have been all over that.'
But this way, her testimony
dies along with her career.
How about you give us
a statement?
Maybe help yourself?
How about you kiss me?
[dramatic music]
You're pretty.
So are you, compared to
most state prison inmates.
[Bosco]
'I hear Minelli's
billing you for the glass.'
[Lisbon]
'It's only fair.'
You know, for a cop, you made
a very convincing lunatic.
Jane must be proud.
Maybe it's not good police work
but I have to confess,
I enjoyed it.
Letting loose for once?
Look, I'm glad you got cleared.
I'm sorry that we couldn't
let you in on the plan.
You could have, but you didn't.
[sighs]
You should know that
if it turned out to be you..
I know.
Just so you do.
[footsteps approach]
Enough said.
I'm not interrupting
anything, am I?
No. Night, Lisbon.
Night, Sam.
- Donuts from Marie's.
- Oh!
I didn't see it, of course.
What?
- He's in love with you.
- Don't be silly.
I know, hard to fathom,
but, uh..
...there's no accounting
for taste, is there?
Hush!
[instrumental music]
[Jane]
Stay tuned for scenes
from our next episode.
[theme music]